Heading into the slope is No. 8, Satono Diamond.
好的 爬上坡道的是8號的里見光鑽
No. 3, Super Mate isn't going to let this chance slip by either.
接著是瞄準這個瞬間的 3號默契之交
Jewel Spinel is on the inside line
珠寶尖晶在內側
while Divinity is on the flank.
外側則是神力
200 meters left for this Japanese Derby.
日本德比剩下不到200公尺了
What a powerful acceleration.
好厲害的加速
Go, Diamond, go!
光鑽 衝啊
You can do this, Diamond!
一定要成功 光鑽
Get your first G1.
妳一定要拿下里見的第一個GI
Super Mate bolts out from the middle.
然而默契之交從中間衝了出來
Satono Diamond is in the lead right now.
爭奪領先位置的 是8號的里見光鑽
Alongside Super Mate, who goes neck and neck with Satono Diamond.
以及從內側衝出 和她不分軒輊的默契之交
Super Mate has a slight edge.
默契之交稍微領先
Satono Diamond is slowly losing her advantage.
緊追不捨的里見光鑽 慢慢被拉開了距離
Satono Diamond and Super Mate
里見光鑽 默契之交
crossed the finishing line at the same time!
現在同時衝過終點
Who won? Will it be Super Mate
獲勝的會是默契之交
or No. 8, Satono Diamond?
還是8號的里見光鑽呢
They seemingly crossed the line together.
兩人幾乎是同時抵達終點
Behind them, Divinity takes the third spot.
稍微落後的神力則是第三名
"RACE REPLAY" This is…
(判定照片) 這是…
"1ST: SUPER MATE" It's Super Mate!
(第一名 默契之交) (第二名 里見光鑽) 是默契之交
-Yay! -Super Mate is the winner.
-太好了 -最後贏家是3號默契之交
What a nail-biter! We needed a replay to determine the winner.
這是場激烈到 要靠照片來進行判定的戰鬥
No. 8, Satono Diamond was so close behind
8號里見光鑽以些微之差緊追其後
but she failed to secure the first spot.
但還是沒能夠反敗為勝
Diamond…
光鑽…
The champion of this year's Japanese Derby is Super Mate!
站上世代頂點 贏下日本德比的賽馬娘是默契之交
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《賽馬娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
EPISODE 5: PROOF OF MY WORTH
(第5話 自我的證明)
"DARING TACT" That was so close, Diamond.
(謀勇兼備) 真是太可惜了 光鑽
You would have won it
要不是馬蹄鐵壞掉 妳肯定會贏的
What's the point of dwelling on what-ifs?
別去假設這些狀況比較好
But…
但是…
It was only 8cm…
就只差這八公分…
Is it the curse of Satono?
里見的魔咒嗎
The curse that the Satonos can never win G1?
是指里見的賽馬娘 無法贏得GI的那件事嗎
I hate to say it, but everyone can't help but think that way.
雖然不甘心 但也難怪會被別人這樣這麼說
The same happened back then.
那個時候也是…
And it happened to Diamond, too, in Satsuki Sho.
參加今年皐月賞的光鑽也是
It's like the higher being is messing with us.
就像是神明真在阻饒我們一樣
No.
沒事的
I will break the curse.
我會打破那個詛咒的
I will win Kikuka Sho.
我一定會贏下菊花賞的
Diamond…
光鑽…
She doesn't give up.
絕對不會挫敗的心
She has a firm resolution.
不會粉碎的信念
Diamond is so awesome.
光鑽果然很厲害
So I should work harder too.
好 我也要加油
Your best record yet, Kita.
是最佳時間耶 小北
Is that so?
真的嗎
Yay!
太好了
Your speed and stamina have improved.
速度和體力都大幅提升了呢
It's all thanks to the intensive training.
都是那次特訓的成果呢
Yes.
是啊
After winning Tenno Sho in spring, you now have two victories in G1.
贏下春季天皇賞後 現在是GI兩勝
You are getting more and more confident too.
妳也越跑越有自信了
You are a representative of this generation, Kitasan.
妳能算是這個世代的代表了吧 北部
Me? For real?
我…我嗎
Keep it up and win Takarazuka Kinen too.
妳就維持現在這個狀態 去贏得接下來的寶塚紀念吧
Y... Yes!
好…好的
Speaking of Takarazuka Kinen, that was where I shone too.
說到寶塚紀念 那可是我一枝獨秀的舞台
As my apprentice, you have to win it.
身為我黃金船的弟子 那是一定要贏的
Since when did you become Kitasan's mentor?
妳是什麼時候變成北部的師父的
What if Kitasan breaks the horse gate?
要是北部撞壞閘門的話要怎麼辦
Kitasan, where are you going?
北部 妳要去哪裡
I'm going for a jog.
我要再去跑步
She's still running after a whole day of training.
都跑這麼多了 還要再跑啊
She has bottomless stamina.
她的體力真是深不見底呢
Yeah.
是啊
She overcame that wall, after all.
畢竟她跨越了那道牆呢
After Tenno Sho comes Takarazuka Kinen.
春季天皇賞後就是寶塚紀念
Will I defeat the others?
我能跑贏她們嗎
Hello. How are you?
哈囉 你好嗎
Sorry, but where's Hanshin Racecourse?
不好意思 請問阪神競馬場在哪裡
Okay…
OK…
"YOU'RE HERE, TOKYO" Here.
(現在在這裡 東京) (阪神競馬場) 在這裡
"HANSHIN RACECOURSE" Here?
(現在在這裡 東京) (阪神競馬場) 在這裡啊
Bye.
BYE
Thank you so much.
真的很感謝妳
Have I become stronger?
我有變強了嗎
Maybe I have.
我可能真的變強了
Recovering from her wrist fracture, the fearsome horse girl
從雙腿橈骨遠端骨折的傷勢中 在今年春天復活的那個怪物
is returning to G1.
終於要回歸國內的GI戰線了
Today, our special guest is Duramente, who will take part in Takarazuka Kinen.
今天邀請到 決定參加寶塚紀念的大鳴大放
"SPECIAL PROGRAM" Joining us is Air Groove, Duramente's
(直播特別採訪) (二冠賽馬娘大鳴大放捲土重來) 還有從小就認識大鳴大放
"DOUBLE CROWN DURAMENTE'S COMEBACK" childhood friend and senior.
(直播特別採訪) (二冠賽馬娘大鳴大放捲土重來) 身為她的前輩的氣槽
I will be conducting this special interview.
在這場直播中做個特別訪問
-Duramente will race in Takarazuka Kinen? -Woah.
-大鳴大放要出賽寶塚紀念嗎 -真的假的
Nine months after her injury,
從那場骨折悲劇後過了九個月
Duramente won her first comeback match in Nakayama Kinen.
漂亮地贏下了中山紀念的復出戰
And during the final in Dubai,
接著在杜拜的決戰
despite a little mishap,
雖說出了點意外
Duramente still finished second against the best European horse girls.
但面對被稱為歐洲最強賽馬娘 還是以出色表現拿下第二名
She has achieved a stellar result in her first international race.
大鳴大放在第一次國外遠征 就拿下了佳績呢
It's just second place.
是第二名
Huh?
什麼
Nothing to write home about.
一點也不出色
Uhm…
可是…那個…
What she means
她的意思是說
is that it was such an honour to learn from the best European horse girls
"能和歐洲最強賽馬娘交手" "是很寶貴的經驗"
and her performance had renewed the confidence in her.
"取得第二名這個佳績" "能夠給她帶來極大的自信"
I see.
原…原來如此
Duramente, your next race will be Takarazuka Kinen.
那個 大鳴大放接下來參加的比賽 是寶塚紀念
What kind of race have you prepared for your eager fans?
您想讓全國引頸期盼的粉絲們 看到一場什麼樣的比賽呢
Absolute victory.
獲勝
Is that all?
那…那個 就只有這樣嗎
What she means
她的意思是說
is that she hopes to show everyone her improvements and win the race.
"會讓大家看見進化後的自己" "以壓倒性的方式取得勝利"
Among all the horse girls my mother tutored,
大鳴大放是我母親 所指導的所有賽馬娘中
Duramente is the most promising one.
其才能最為出類拔萃的賽馬娘
I am sure you will witness her coolness in action again during Takarazuka Kinen.
想必一定能在寶塚紀念裡 讓粉絲看見她不同凡響的表現
I sure can't wait.
原來如此 還真是令人期待
Speaking of Takarazuka Kinen,
關於這場寶塚紀念
the horse girl who has been slowly improving in Duramente's absence,
在大鳴大放休養期間裡 提升不少實力的菊花賞賽馬娘
Kitasan Black, will also be in it.
北部玄駒也預計將要參賽
Both of them have two wins in G1,
兩位同是GI兩勝
so it'll be a duel between the best of the best.
將會是場同世代的巔峰對決
What do you think of it?
請說說您現在的想法吧
I don't care who my enemy is.
對手是誰都無所謂
She means to say that Takarazuka Kinen had a lot of talented horse girls,
她的意思是說 "寶塚紀念會有很多高手參賽"
so she wouldn't…
"所以這場比賽她也不會…"
These races are the necessary steps to Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
所有的比賽 都不過是通往凱旋門賞的過程
I will show everyone
我會向大家證明
a performance that transcends words
什麼是就連"強大 快速" 這些名詞也無法形容的力量
and what it means to be the absolute best.
以及任誰都能一目了然的"最強"
Where are you going, Duramente?
妳要去哪裡 大鳴
The interview is not over.
採訪還沒結束呢
I'm going back to my training, Groove.
我要回去練習了 槽姐
Don't call me that on camera!
不…不要在鏡頭這樣叫我啦
-Cut. Cut. -Wait for me.
-快卡掉 -喂 等等我…
-Cut the camera. -Did you hear
-請把拍攝機關掉 -你有聽到她最後說的話嗎
"PLEASE WAIT" what she said?
(請稍候) -請把拍攝機關掉 -你有聽到她最後說的話嗎
Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
凱旋門賞
Is that Duramente's goal?
大鳴大放的目標果然是這個嗎
How exciting.
真令人是期待
What a killer interview.
這場訪問真是不得了
Yeah.
是啊
"These races are the necessary steps to Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe," she said.
居然說"所有的比賽" "都不過是通往凱旋門賞的過程"
Yeah.
是啊
I can understand her.
我懂她想表達什麼啦
After all, Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe is the most prestigious tournament.
畢竟凱旋門賞 是世界最高峰的比賽嘛
Unless you have joined it, you won't understand the honour.
沒去跑過的人是無法理解的啦
You won't endure this provocation silently, will you, Kitasan?
被人說成這樣 肯定是嚥不下這口氣對吧 北部
That's right. You can't lose to an egoistic person like Duramente.
是啊 妳可別輸給那種失禮的人喔
Yes. I won't lose.
好…好的 我絕對不會輸的
Well, I sure hope I won't lose.
我是很想這樣說啦
Duramente is so… strong.
但是大鳴大放…她真的很強呢
Yeah.
的確
In Satsuki Sho, Duramente might be a bit reckless,
皐月賞時的大鳴大放雖然粗曠
but there's more to her than meets the eye.
但給人一種深不可測的感覺
-Yeah. -It feels like she unleashed everything
-是啊 -而在日本德比時她的才能完全釋放
and won the Japanese Derby.
取得那場壓倒性的勝利
-Yup. -And she missed Kikuka Sho
-是啊 -無論是菊花賞還是春季的天皇賞
and Tenno Sho.
大鳴大放也都沒有出賽
I haven't been able to defeat her.
我一次也沒有贏過那個人
The Kitasan from last year couldn't defeat her.
但沒贏過她的 是去年的北部
Right?
對吧
That's right, Kita.
就是啊 小北
You have improved a lot.
妳不是提升了不少實力嗎
-Yup. -You are bigger now too.
-是啊 -身體也大了一圈
You're not the Kitasan from last year anymore.
跟去年相比已經是截然不同了
Exactly.
是啊
Look.
妳看
"VOTING RESULT:" You are voted the fan favourite
(粉絲投票 北部玄駒 82121票) 妳奪下了"歡迎來到寶塚紀念"
"KITASAN BLACK, 82,121 VOTES" in Welcome to Takarazuka Kinen.
粉絲投票的第一名呢
Not bad, my dear apprentice.
幹得不錯嘛 我的弟子
When did you become her mentor?
妳到底是什麼時候 變成她的師父的
What if she makes goofy faces when she's racing?
要是她在奔跑出露出怪表情怎麼辦
82,000 votes…
八萬兩千票…
That's a lot.
這麼多…
Everyone wants to see you there.
大家都很期待妳的表現
They want to see the Kitasan Black who won Kikuka Sho and Tenno Sho.
期待奪下菊花賞以及春季天皇賞 的北部玄駒
You.
也就是妳
Guys…
大家…
Oh, no.
怎麼辦
I don't have an umbrella with me.
我沒有帶傘耶
What to do…
傷腦筋…
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《賽馬娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
Uhm…
那…那個
It's raining.
雨…一直在下呢
Yes.
是啊
I forgot to bring my umbrella.
那個…我忘了帶傘
Did you forget yours too, Duramente?
大鳴大放…妳也是嗎
Yes.
是啊
So we're the same.
那我們是一樣的呢
I… I watched your interview.
那個…我看過妳的採訪了
You're so amazing, Duramente.
大鳴大放 妳真的很厲害
You proclaimed confidently that you want to be the absolute best.
能這樣自信滿滿地說出 "要證明什麼是最強"
Do you feel no fear?
妳…都不會害怕嗎
What if you lost in the race
那個…就是輸掉比賽
or couldn't meet their expectations?
或是無法回應眾人的期待
I have never thought about that.
我沒想過
Wow.
妳真的…很厲害呢
Because this is my duty,
因為那是我的使命
my distance dream,
遙遠的夢想
my clan's instinct to constantly push beyond my limit.
不斷向極限挑戰的我族心願
It's in my blood.
就在我的血脈之中流動
I have to challenge the mantle of the absolute best,
去贏得 不斷挑戰之路前方的最強證明
Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
凱旋門賞
I was born for it.
我是為了贏得凱旋門賞而存在的
That's all.
僅此而已
Even if I lose, I won't stop marching forward.
就算是輸也不能停止前進
I'm here to retrieve what I forgot to bring with me.
我是來拿回忘記帶走的東西
I couldn't compete in Kikuka Sho.
我沒能參加菊花賞
Therefore…
所以
I am the best horse girl of our generation.
我依然還是世代最強
And to prove it, I'll defeat the champion of Kikuka Sho.
我要打敗菊花賞賽馬娘 藉此證明這一點
Then, I will go beyond and win Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
接著挑戰世界 奪下凱旋門賞
The determination to reach for her dream.
不停向夢想挑戰的心
Her unwavering faith.
絕對不會停止的信念
She's honest, beautiful,
既率直 又漂亮
and strong.
而且強大
Duramente takes part in Takarazuka Kinen
這樣的大鳴大放 為了要與我一決勝負
so that she can race against me.
而來參加寶塚紀念…
But…
但是…
I trained and improved a lot in the past year too.
我也在這一年裡吃了很多 實力也提升了不少
Don't go thinking that you can defeat me that easily.
妳別以為可以輕易地贏過我喔
Who are you?
妳是誰
Huh?
什麼
Wait… You don't know me?
那個…難道說妳不認識我嗎
I don't.
是啊
I am Kitasan Black.
我…我是北部玄駒
The Kitasan Black that won Kikuka Sho.
我就那個菊花賞賽馬娘 北部玄駒啦
I see.
這樣啊
Duramente,
大鳴大放
I will show you what I'm capable of.
我會讓妳見識我的實力的
I will defeat you so that you will remember my name!
我要贏過妳 讓妳記得我北部玄駒這個賽馬娘
See you in Takarazuka Kinen!
那我們就寶塚紀念見了
She doesn't give a damn about me.
她完全沒把我放在眼裡
I will give my all.
我要使出我的全力
I will show her the new version of me,
使出不同於去年的我的全力
everything!
我的一切
Diamond.
光鑽
I won't let you shoulder everything alone.
我不會只讓妳一個人背負一切的
I must break our family curse this time.
我這次一定要…打破里見的魔咒
I'll prove it to all of you,
讓妳們見識一下
to my sister and Vivlos
給姊姊還有強擊看看
that I can win.
我贏下偉大勝利瞬間
Honouring the wishes of their loyal fans,
將被粉絲選上的榮耀置於心中
bearing everyone's dreams on their shoulders,
把被托付的夢想握在手中
on this wonderful day gather 17 horse girls at Hanshin Racecourse.
在初夏的藍天下 集結於阪神競馬場的17位賽馬娘
Takarazuka Kinen, the final chapter that concludes the first half of G1
總結上半期賽事的比賽 寶塚紀念
will begin soon.
馬上就要開始了
Duramente and Kitasan Black.
大鳴大放和北部玄駒
This will be the duel of two double-crowned horse girls.
這場比賽將是 同為GI兩勝賽馬娘的對決
Kitasan Black is the fans' favourite,
在粉絲投票上 是由北部玄駒獲得第一
but more people cheer for Duramente here.
但在當日人氣上 是由大鳴大放拔得頭籌
This is their first race together after a year.
畢竟這是她們相隔一年的對決
I can't wait to see what new things they will bring to the table.
我們期待各自有所成長的她們 會有什麼樣的精彩表現
The track is slightly sticky.
場地略黏呢
Yeah.
是啊
It favours Kitasan's strength and stamina.
肯定會對北部的力量和體力較為有利
But Duramente is a beast so…
但是對手是那個怪物…
Don't be intimidated by her, Kitasan.
可別在氣勢上輸人了喔 北部
The festival girl, Kitasan Black.
祭典女孩 北部玄駒
And the returning champion, Duramente.
歸來怪物 大鳴大放
Who will win?
獲勝的將會是哪一位賽馬娘呢
Takarazuka Kinen, a race that carries the dreams of many fans
好的 承載了粉絲 和通往世界夢想的比賽
and the ticket to greater heights.
寶塚紀念
It begins now!
現在 起跑了
Everyone is vying for the lead.
首先是爭奪領先地位
Kitasan Black is off to a good start.
北部玄駒起跑得很漂亮
She is currently in the lead.
位於第一引領著這場比賽
Good.
好
It is the first stretch.
最初的直線跑道
Fans are cheering loudly for these 17 athletes.
粉絲正用熱烈的歡呼 迎接這17位選手
Kitasan Black!
北部玄駒…
-Go! -Kita!
-衝啊… -小北…
Kitasan Black is in the lead.
領先的是北部玄駒
No. 4, Single Lonely, takes the second place.
第二名是4號單身孤寂
Then, No. 10, Canon Millefeuille.
10號卡農千層
No. 5, Cheval Grand.
5號高尚駿逸
Duramente is behind the centre, right after the fourth place.
大鳴大放位於馬群中段後方 現在在後方的第四位
Behind her is Satono Crown. We're now in the first bend.
里見皇冠則是緊跟其後 進入第一彎道
Kitasan is accelerating while Duramente preserves her energy for the final sprint.
加速飛奔的北部 保留實力的大鳴大放
They use two different approaches.
兩人的跑法截然不同
The current first place, Kitasan Black, is leading by two horse lengths.
暫列第一的北部玄駒 領先後方兩個馬身
After the second bend, she will head into another stretch.
過了第二彎道後 就要進入非終點直道
No. 4, Single Lonely, takes the second place.
第二名為4號單身孤寂
Then, No. 10, Canon Millefeuille.
10號卡農千層
No. 11, South Fox is on the flank, alongside Cheval Grand.
接著是外側的11號南方狐 以及和她並排的高尚駿逸
Behind them
而在中後段馬群之中
is the ambitious beast, Duramente.
她在這裡 放眼世界的怪物 大鳴大放
Satono Crown is giving chase too.
里見皇冠也緊追不放
The record for the first 1,000 meters is 59.1 seconds.
前半1000公尺成績為59秒1
Not even one minute.
不到1分鐘
She's too fast.
會不會太快了
Yes.
是啊
But I'm sure Kitasan will persevere till the end.
不過憑現在的北部 一定能堅持到最後的
Can Kitasan Black keep this up in the latter half of the race?
進入比賽後半段 北部玄駒能堅持到最後嗎
In Derby, I only looked at what was in front of me.
在那次德比的比賽時 我只看得到前面
But now, I can hear the footsteps behind me,
但現在我能聽見 在我身後追趕的所有人
including Duramente's.
還有大鳴大放的腳步聲
Kitasan Black is leading by 1.5 horse length.
北部玄駒位居第一 領先一個半馬身
But No. 16, River Light, accelerated at the fourth bend.
但就在第四彎道前 16號光明河流追了上來
Duramente is still at the centre.
而大鳴大放依然在馬群之中
My breathing is stable. My feet are light.
呼吸沒有紊亂 腳步也很輕盈
I will show her what I can do and win this race.
我要讓她見識我的實力 並且贏下勝利
-Now! -Let's do this.
-就是現在 -一決勝負吧
Leaving the final bend, they have arrived at the home stretch.
好的 離開最後彎道 來到了直線
Kitasan Black is leading by two horse lengths.
北部玄駒位居第一 領先兩個馬身
The second place is No. 7, Bravo Day.
第二名是7號讚嘆之日
River Light is on the flank
再來是外側的光明河流
with Cheval Grand.
以及高尚駿逸
Satono Crown speeds up on the flank.
里見皇冠則從最外側衝了出來
-Go! -Kita!
-衝啊… -小北…
Keep this up.
就這樣堅持下去
200 meters left.
好的 剩下200公尺
They are heading to the slope.
同時進入上坡道
And right then,
然後就在這個時候
Duramente dashes out from the centre for the first place.
大鳴大放脫離馬群衝向第一
She is out!
她衝出來了
I will cross the finishing line like this.
我要就這樣衝過終點
Duramente!
大鳴大放
Can she close the gap? Duramente!
沒能追上嗎 大鳴大放
Kitasan Black is still in the lead.
領先的依然是北部玄駒
So fast.
好快
But I will overtake you.
但我一定會追過妳的
Kitasan Black is in the lead,
北部玄駒領先
but here comes Duramente!
但是大鳴大放追上來了
I will show you that I'm the strongest.
我要證明我是最強的
Who are you?
妳是誰啊
No. 2, River Light, closes in too.
但是2號光明河流追上來了
River Light!
是光明河流
The winner is neither the festival girl nor the beast,
獲勝的既不是祭典女孩也不是怪物
it's River Light!
而是光明河流
Overtaking Kitasan Black from the inside line
超越內側的北部玄駒
and Duramente on the flank,
而且甩掉了外側大鳴大放的追趕
the winner of this tournament
贏下這場比賽的人
is No. 16, River Light!
是16號 光明河流
Yay!
太好了…
I lost again.
我又輸掉了…
Duramente!
大鳴大放
Duramente, are you all right?
大鳴大放 妳還好嗎
Let's head to the infirmary now.
那個…馬上去醫務室吧
No need.
不用
-But… -I said, no need.
-但是… -我說不用
Duramente, you are amazing.
大鳴大放 妳果然很厲害
You overtook me again.
我又被妳追過了
I lost.
我徹底輸了
Yay!
太好了
You are not too shabby either.
妳也很強
You forced me to run like I have never run before.
妳逼得我不得不奔跑至此
You will now be my checkpoint.
我一直將妳視為一個通過點
That is your purpose.
但看來妳有其存在意義
I am honoured to race with you here.
我很榮幸能在寶塚紀念與妳一戰
I will become stronger.
我會再變得更強
And next time, I will personally hand your defeat to you,
然後下次 我一定會以壓到性的勝利贏過妳
Kitasan Black.
北部玄駒
Duramente…
大鳴大放…
Me too.
我也是
I will become stronger.
我也會繼續變得更強
I won't lose to you again, Duramente.
下次我絕對不會再輸了 大鳴大放
No.
不對
-Thank you, everyone. -I won't lose anymore, Dura.
-謝謝大家 -我絕對不會輸的 小鳴
Dura?
小鳴…
Yes, Dura.
是啊 小鳴
Okay.
好
Yay!
太好了
Thank you for your support.
謝謝大家的加油
Geez.
真是的
What are the second and third place babbling about over there?
一個第二名 一個第三名 是在那邊說什麼呢